head.com 2017-05-23

# Privacy Policy [EN]

HTM Sport GmbH (hereinafter referred to as "HTM"), Tyroliaplatz 1, A2320 Schwechat, Phone: +43/1/701 79-0, is the owner of all websites  of the HEAD group. This website, including its subdomains, databases and webshops (“Website”)  is operated by HTM or its subsidiaries (for details please see the imprint of this Website). 

Access to the Website is granted in the relevant form of availability ("as is, where is and as available") and without any warranty or guarantee, unless this is legally required by law. We assume no responsibility or liability for damage or any other disadvantage resulting from the use of the Website. 

Our data protection notice and our General Terms and Conditions set out how we acquire, use, transfer and protect personal data in relation to this Website. 

**  Acquisition, use and disclosure of personal data**

In general, we acquire, use and transfer personal data upon your consent and/or to the extent to which this is legally permitted or required. 

If you purchase goods on our Website, we acquire, save and process personal data such as your name, billing and delivery address, e-mail address, credit or debit card information and information on the goods you have purchased; we do this to initiate, conclude and fulfil the processing of the sales contract (as well as possible post-contractual obligations) and/or for production purposes in case of Head Custom Made orders. For the delivery of purchased goods, we may disclose your name and your delivery address to transport or courier service providers. We may also disclose your name as well as payment and transaction information to credit or financial institutions in order to process the payment.

If you create an account on our Website, we will acquire the personal data mentioned above in addition to your user name and your password in order to manage your on-line account.

We will use the data provided by you for processing your order. If you subscribe to our newsletter your e-mail-address will be used for promotion purposes until you unsubscribe by giving us notice at any time. 

We also acquire personal data (such as name and contact information) if you take part in a competition or in advertising promotions in order to manage such competition or such advertising promotions and to contact and announce the winners.

If need be, we will also use your personal data:

  * to improve our products and services;

  * for internal statistical or operational purposes to measure and understand demographic, user, user interest, purchase and other trends in relation to our users.

  * to be able to respond to your enquiries and questions;

  * to be able to communicate with you via e-mail if such communication is related to goods which you purchased on our Website, to the status of your account or to amendments of applicable General Terms and Conditions;

  * to provide you with information on products, services, events and advertising promotions in which you might be interested, unless you expressly declared that you do not want to receive such communication from us;

  * to take investigation, prevention, protection and other measures relating to infringements against these General Terms and Conditions, to illegal actions, suspected fraud or situations where a violation of a statutory rights or rights of other persons is very likely; and

  * for all other purposes approved by you and/or to the extent to which this is legally permitted or required.

We may transfer personal data to external vicarious agents or service providers (this shall include HTM subsidiaries operating in this capacity) who provide services on our behalf, such as telecommunication service providers, call centres, billing service providers, marketing agencies, IT service providers and/or data hosting or data processing service providers or providers of similar services and/or service providers who acquire, use, transfer or process personal data in any other way for the purposes described herein. It is possible that some service providers are subject to different jurisdiction. If your personal data is transferred outside your country of residence, these shall be subject to applicable laws in that country which, under certain circumstances, may allow foreign security or execution authorities to access to your personal data. 

Personal data may also be used by and disclosed to parties involved for the purpose of evaluating and/or executing the planned transaction or to parties who take part in the scheduled or actual financing, hedging, insurance, sale, assignment or any other type of disposing parts of or our entire business and/or our assets. Our legal successors or assignees may use and transfer you personal data for the purposes described herein. On our Website, we may also use social network plug-ins ( _e.g._ Facebook, Google, Twitter).

**Acquisition of passive data**

If you visit this Website, we automatically acquire data such as the IP address assigned to your computer, the date and the time of the access to the Website, the browser type, the operating system of your computer and the pages which you accessed. We use this information in order to determine how users surf on this Website as well as for general analysis purposes. This information will not be used to identify you and we will not link it to the personal data mentioned above.

**Cookies and tracking technologies**

Like many other companies, we also use "cookies" on our Website. Cookies are small text files which are saved on your computer hard disk if you access certain websites. Cookies can make the use of websites more convenient by saving your settings while you are visiting a certain website. We use cookies to save the content of your virtual shopping trolley for the next visit on our Website. We also use cookies to measure and determine activities on our Website to see which Website areas and functions users prefer. 

Most browsers inform you of how to reject the acceptance of new cookies, how you can be informed about the receipt of a new cookie and how you can deactivate all existing cookies. However, without cookies it is likely that you will not be able to use all of the functions on our Website. For example: If you deactivate or reject cookies, you will not be able to place an order on our Website. 

We use cookies to provide the services which you require, to save your settings and to improve and update our Website. In the following, you will find a list indicating some cookies which we use, including the reasons for their use. 

**COOKIE name**

| 

**COOKIE description**  
  
---|---  
  
**CART**

| 

Allocation to your shopping trolley  
  
**CATEGORY_INFO**

| 

Saves information on categories on the website by which pages can be loaded more quickly  
  
**COMPARE**

| 

Products which you have saved to your product comparison list  
  
**CURRENCY**

| 

Your preferred currency  
  
**CUSTOMER**

| 

An encrypted version of your customer ID in the shop  
  
**CUSTOMER_AUTH**

| 

Indicates whether you are currently logged on to the shop  
  
**CUSTOMER_INFO**

| 

An encrypted version of the customer group to which you belong  
  
**CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS**

| 

Saves the customer segment ID  
  
**EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE**

| 

Indicates whether caching is permitted or not  
  
**FRONTEND**

| 

Your session ID on the server  
  
**GEOIP**

| 

Code of the current delivery country  
  
**GUEST-VIEW**

| 

Enables guests to edit their orders  
  
**LAST_CATEGORY**

| 

The last category you visited  
  
**LAST_PRODUCT**

| 

The last product which you accessed  
  
**NEWMESSAGE**

| 

Indicates whether you have received a new message  
  
**NO_CACHE**

| 

Indicates whether caching is permitted  
  
**PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART**

| 

A link to information on your shopping trolley and visited products if you have sent enquiries to the site  
  
**POLL**

| 

The ID from surveys in which you might have taken part  
  
**POLLN**

| 

Information on which poll you took part in  
  
**RECENTLYCOMPARED**

| 

Products that you recently compared  
  
**STF**

| 

Information on products which you sent to friends via e-mail  
  
**STORE**

| 

The store view or language you selected  
  
**UNIT**

| 

The selected measuring unit system  
  
**USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE**

| 

Indicates whether a customer has accepted cookies  
  
**VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS**

| 

Products which you have recently viewed  
  
**WISHLIST**

| 

An encrypted list of products which you have added to your wish list  
  
**WISHLIST_CNT**

| 

The number of products in your wish list  
  
User_token, Browser_id, JSESSIONID: These cookies are required if you want to place an order. We use them so that you can save products to your shopping trolley, so that your visits on this Website and the content of the shopping trolley are saved and so that you can efficiently navigate this Website. If we did not use these cookies, you would not be able to place an order on our Website.

Most browsers inform you of how to reject the acceptance of new cookies, how you can be informed about the receipt of a new cookie and how you deactivate all existing cookies. For additional information on settings relating to cookies using your web browser, please go to: http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ge/.

If you have questions or comments relating to this issue, please contact us in the way indicated under "Access, correction and contacting us" below.

**Safety and saving of personal data**

We take appropriate physical, organisational and technical security measures to protect your personal data from loss or theft as well as from unauthorised access, transfer, reproduction, use or modification. HTM and their subsidiaries’ authorised employees, vicarious agents and authorised representatives have access to your personal data if it is necessary to have access to your personal data to perform their operational tasks.

Personal data which we collect on our Website will be saved until the purpose for which these data are acquired is fulfilled, unless other company or statutory retention provisions apply which require a longer retention period. 

  **Access, correction and contacting us**

You have the right to information over the data stored as well as the right to delete and correct the data saved concerning your person. If you want to obtain information regarding your personal data please send an inquiry to one of the following addresses: HTM Sport GmbH, attention of “Legal Department”, Tyroliaplatz 1, A-2320 Schwechat or privacy@head.com. To ensure that personal data is not shared with any unauthorized third party, please enclose with your request details that allow us to clearly identify you as an individual.  

**Google Analytics**

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use and data privacy can be found at <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html> or at <https://www.google.de/intl/en_uk/policies/>. Please note that on this Website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “anonymizeIp” to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking).

This Website uses Universal Analytics (and Google Remarketing), (a) web analysis service(s) offered by Google Inc. ("Google"). Universal Analytics uses so-called "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. Information on the use of the website obtained by the cookie (including your IP address) are generally transmitted to US-based server and saved there.

If IP address anonymisation is activated (as it is on this Website), the last octet of your IP address will be truncated/anonymised by Google within the member states of the European Union and in other European Economic Area countries before being transmitted to the US. Only in exceptional cases will Google transmit complete IP addresses to the United States and shorten them there. On the website operator's behalf, Google will use this information to evaluate how you use this website to create website activity reports and to provide additional services to the website operator which are related to the website and internet use.

Your IP address, which is transferred by Universal Analytics, will not be associted with other data obtained by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, we would like to point out that, in this case, you may not be able to use all functions of the website. In addition, you can also block a saving of all data which were created by cookies and which relate to the use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of these data by Google. In order to do so, simply download and install the browser plug-in offered under the following link: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this Website: <a href=”javascript:gaOptout()”>Disable Google Analytics</a>

Furthermore we may use Google Analytics to assess the data obtained via Google AdWords and the Double-Click-Cookie for statistical purposes. To avoid such use please install the advertising opt-out plugin offered under the following link: http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en. For additional information relating to the terms of use and data protection, please go to <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html> or https://www.google.de/intl/en-GB/policies/. Please note that on this Website, Google Analytics code is supplemented by “anonymizeIp” to ensure an anonymized collection of IP addresses (so called IP-masking). 

(Source: [www.datenschutzbeauftragter-info.de](https://www.datenschutzbeauftragter-info.de/ "Datenschutzbeauftragter INFO"))

**Google Remarketing**

This Website uses cookies for the purpose of addressing visitors again at a later time in Google advertisement networks through re-marketing campaigns including on-line advertisements. Third-party suppliers such as Google use cookies on the basis of a visit of the relevant website to publish re-marketing advertisements. As a user, you can deactivate the use of cookies by Google by going to the Google deactivation website at http://www.google.com/ads/preferences.

**Data protection notice for the use of Facebook plug-ins (Like button)**

We have integrated plug-ins offered by the social network Facebook, 1601 South California, Palo Alto, California, 94304, USA, into our Website. Such Facebook plug-ins can be recognised by their Facebook logo or the "Like button" on our Website. For an overview of all Facebook plug-ins, please refer to [http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/](http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/). If you visit our Website, this plug-in sets up a direct link between your browser and the Facebook server. In this way, Facebook is informed that you visited our Website with your IP address. If you click on the Facebook "Like button" while you are logged on to your Facebook account, you may link the contents on our Website to your Facebook profile. This enables Facebook to assign the visit on our Website to your user account. We would like to emphasise that we do not receive any information about the content of transmitted data or their use by Facebook. For additional information, please refer to the Facebook data protection notice at [http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php](http://de-de.facebook.com/policy.php)  
  
If you do not wish Facebook to be able to assign the visit on our websites to your Facebook account, please log out of your Facebook account.

**Data protection notice for the use of Google +1**

Information saving and transfer: By clicking on the Google +1 button you can disseminate the information worldwide. Through the Google +1 button, you and other users receive personalised contents from Google and our partners. Google will save the information that you clicked on +1 for a certain content as well as information on the website which you were visiting when clicking on +1. Your +1 may be shown together with your profile name and your photo on Google services, such as search results or on your Google profile or on other websites and online advertisements. Google collects information on your +1 activities to improve its services for you and others. In order to be able to use the Google +1 button, you need to have a globally visible, public Google profile which has to contain at least the chosen profile name. This name will be used in all Google services. In some cases, this name may substitute other names which you used for sharing contents on your Google account. Your Google profile identity may be shown to users who know your e-mail address or who dispose of other identifying information about you.  
  
Use of collected information: In addition to the uses mentioned above, information provided by you will be used according to applicable Google data protection rules. Google may publish summarised statistics on +1 user activities or share them with third parties and partners, such as publishers, advertisers or associated websites.

**Twitter data protection notice**

Our websites have Twitter functions embedded. These functions are offered by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St, Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. By using Twitter and the "re-tweet" function, websites visited by you are linked to your Twitter account and shown to others. In this case, data are also transmitted to Twitter.  
  
We would like to emphasise that we do not receive any information about the content of transmitted data or their use by Twitter. For further information, please refer to the Twitter data protection notice at [http://twitter.com/privacy](http://twitter.com/privacy).

You can change your Twitter privacy settings in your account settings at [http://twitter.com/account/settings](http://twitter.com/account/settings).

Dated: November 2015
